Guide to the Hattie Lel Red letters to Mr. Edward H. Phillips, 1970-1980 MS 073
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Hattie Lel Red letters to Mr. Edward H. Phillips
1970-1980
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Red, Hattie Lel
MS 073
0.1 Linear Feet 1 folder (9 letters)
The letters concern Ms. Hattie Lel Red's scholarship fund raising activities on behalf of Dr. Edward Phillips' history students at Austin College and his responses thereto. Her letters also cover her memories of her time at Rice and of her family, classmates and teachers, as well as comments concerning her travels in Texas and elsewhere.
Biographical Note
Ms. Hattie Lel Red was born January 14, 1894. A native Houstonian, she was the daughter of Dr. C.S. Red, a prominent physician and founder of the Harris County Medical Society. She was the first woman to receive a diploma in the first graduating class at Rice Institute in 1916. She graduated with the distinction in mathematics and later received an advanced degree from Columbia University. She taught high school mathematics, retiring from teaching in 1964 at Lamar High School in Houston. Following retirement she continued active in professional, social, and patriotic organizations. She died October 4, 1990. During the Period of their correspondence Dr. Edward Hake Phillips was Professor of History at Austin College, Sherman, Texas.
Scope and Contents
The letters concern Ms. Hattie Lel Red's scholarship fund raising activities on behalf of Dr. Edward Phillips' history students at Austin College and his responses thereto. Her letters also cover her memories of her time at Rice and of her family, classmates and teachers, as well as comments concerning her travels in Texas and elsewhere.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Professor Edward H. Phillips, April 1988
Index Terms
Subjects
Education; Rice University -- History; Women; Universities and colleges
Document Types
corrrespondence
Subjects (Persons)
Red, Hattie Lel
- Series I: Hattie Lel Red letters to Mr. Edward H. Phillips, 1970-1980, 11110
  - Hattie Lel Red to Edward Hake Phillips, July 21, 1977, 11119 (Folder 1)
  - Edward Hake Phillips to Hattie Lel Red, May 2, 1978, 11118 (Folder 1)
  - Hattie Lel Red to Edward Hake Phillips, June 11, 1978, 11117 (Folder 1)
  - Hattie Lel Red to Edward Hake Phillips, April 7, 1979, 11116 (Folder 1)
  - Hattie Lel Red to Edward Hake Phillips, May 21, 1979, 11115 (Folder 1)
  - Hattie Lel Red to Edward Hake Phillips, April 29 (or 30), 1980, envelope only. Letter apparently forwarded to Austin College Business Office or department chairman., 11114 (Folder 1)
  - Hattie Lel Red to Edward Hake Phillips, July 17, 1980, 11113 (Folder 1)
  - Hattie Lel Red to Edward Hake Phillips, March 14, 1981, 11112 (Folder 1)
  - Hattie Lel Red to Edward Hake Phillips, October 5, 1982, 11111 (Folder 1)